[theme music playing]
LOVE NEXT DOOR
[humming]
What's this?
Hye-suk's things must've got into my bag.
What is this? It's all in English.
Does she carry this around
to show off how she can read it?
She's such a brat. [clicks tongue]
[magazine rustling]
"The…"
[groans softly]
Where was Seok-ryu's
old electronic dictionary?
Why does she have so much medicine?
[solemn music playing]
-[pills rattling]
-Are they all vitamins? What are these?
Damn it. These are all in English too.
[scoffs]
[phone vibrating]
HYE-SUK
Jeez, you brat. Speak of the devil.
Hey, Hye-suk.
What? Seung-hyo's sick?
-Thank you so much.
-[scoffs]
He's sick.
But how can I make him porridge?
I've never tried.
You made a good decision.
He always gets sick around this time.
-Really?
-Yeah.
Strangely,
it's always in summer, not winter.
He had a fever of 40 degrees once.
Geun-sik and I had to carry him
to your husband's hospital.
[exhales]
By the way, I almost forgot.
You left a magazine
written in English in my bag.
A magazine?
I never did that.
You probably took it.
Why would I take that? It's useless.
-[Seung-hyo] We need to talk.
-[Seok-ryu] Let's talk later.
I think Seok-ryu's inside.
-Seok-ryu's here?
-Yeah.
[Seung-hyo] How long
were you going to hide this for?
Seung-hyo. [inhales]
[voice shaking] This doesn't make sense.
How could you go through something
like that without telling anyone?
Stomach cancer surgery is serious.
How could you not tell anyone?
[Mi-suk] Who has cancer?
[door closes]
[emotional music playing]
[Mi-suk] I heard it from outside.
Stomach cancer?
Who has cancer?
Is it you?
Is it really you?
[whimpering]
[both crying hysterically]
[Seok-ryu crying]
-[sniffles]
-Seok-ryu, let's go to the hospital.
-Hye-suk, call your husband.
-Okay.
Tell him we're coming right now, okay?
-[Hye-suk] Okay.
-Mom, I'm fine.
I don't have to go.
What do you mean? Why not?
Seung-hyo, get the car.
We have to go to the hospital now.
No, Mom. I'm fine.
I already had the surgery. I'm okay.
What are you talking about? When?
[voice shaking] Three years ago.
Three years ago?
But that's when you were in the US.
No way.
How could I not know about that?
[Mi-suk's breath trembling]
Is it true?
Really?
[voice shaking] I'm sorry, Mom.
I'm so sorry.
Seung-hyo, did you know?
Did you both lie to me again this time?
[voice shaking] No, I didn't know.
I just found out.
[groans softly]
-[Seok-ryu crying] Mom!
-Mi-suk!
Mi-suk, are you okay?
-Mi-suk.
-[Seok-ryu] Mom!
-[Hye-suk] Where are you going, Mi-suk?
-Mom!
-[Hye-suk] Mi-suk!
[Hye-suk] Seung-hyo.
[Seung-hyo sighs]
-[door opens]
-[both laughing]
Mom! Listen to me!
I can explain everything.
Okay? Mom, please!
-Please, don't.
-[Mi-suk] Honey.
-[Geun-sik] What?
-Honey, she has cancer.
[breathing heavily]
[exhales]
What are you talking about?
Hey, what did your mom say?
[breathing heavily]
She had stomach cancer.
She received surgery
three years ago without telling us.
That's ridiculous.
[breathing heavily]
[exhales]
Seok-ryu.
-It's not true, is it?
-[Seok-ryu sniffles]
[Geun-sik] It's not true, right?
This is… [chuckles nervously] No. No way.
What on earth are you saying?
[Dong-jin] Hey, Seok-ryu.
This is a prank, right?
Why would you joke
about something serious like that?
[Mi-suk groans]
[exhales]
[crying] Mom!
[groans]
[breathing heavily]
[Seok-ryu] Mom!
[exhales]
[inhales]
[Seok-ryu inhales]
[breathing heavily]
Is this why you didn't want to
go to the bathhouse?
Mom, this…
It'll fade.
They said it'll hardly
be noticeable later.
[pills rattling]
What are all these pills?
Why do you have so much?
-Is it because you're sick?
-[Seok-ryu] No.
I'm not sick at all now.
[Mi-suk] Then, why do you have so much?
They're just liver supplements,
probiotics, and vitamins.
Don't leave anything out
and tell me the truth.
What happened to you?
Three years ago,
I had a health checkup in the US.
-And I was diagnosed with stomach cancer.
-[cries]
I had surgery,
and it turned out to be stage 2.
I underwent chemotherapy as a precaution.
But I overcame it.
I'm completely fine now.
Is that why your engagement
was called off? Because you were sick?
-[voice shaking] I'll kill that bastard!
-[Seok-ryu] No, it wasn't like that.
He stayed by my side while I was sick.
He took time off work
and cared for me.
And…
I didn't want to make him suffer anymore.
-So I called the marriage off.
-Do you think parents are a joke?
How…
How could you hide
something like this from us?
I wasn't trying to.
I was going to get treated in the US.
-You'd only worry if you knew.
-Who cares if it was the US?
If their child is sick,
a parent would go
to the moon or Mars for them.
How dare you be so arrogant
and pretend you did this for us?
[voice shaking] Mom.
[Mi-suk] Listen.
You were once a part of me.
While you were in my womb,
you ate the food I ate.
And you drank the water
I drank as you grew.
[sniffles]
I endured 20 hours of labor
before an emergency C-section.
But how could you not tell me
you were sick?
[voice shaking] How? How could I not know?
[sniffles]
I'm sorry, Mom. [crying]
Dad, I'm sorry.
[voice shaking] You should've told us.
You should've told us what was happening.
No matter how useless we are
as your parents…
Still, we should've known.
She thinks she's better than us,
so she doesn't see us as her parents.
No, don't say that. [crying]
I just couldn't tell you.
I couldn't bear to do it.
I wanted to tell you after I got better.
That's what happened.
[sniffles]
I was wrong, Mom. I'm sorry.
[cries]
Goodness.
[whimpering, crying]
[emotional music playing]
-[Dong-jin] Mom.
-[crying]
[footsteps fading]
[sniffles]
Seok-ryu.
[whimpering, sniffles]
[voice shaking] Are you really okay now?
There aren't any problems, right?
Yeah, I'm healthy now. I'm fine.
You don't have to worry.
Okay. [sniffles]
Then, that'll do.
[Seok-ryu groans softly]
That'll do.
[breath trembling]
[breathing heavily]
Mom, drink some water.
[breath trembling]
[breathing heavily]
[emotional music continues playing]
-[door closes]
-[sighs]
[breathing heavily]
[sniffles]
[groans softly]
[sniffles, exhales]
[playing drums]
[faint drum sounds]
[faint drum sounds continue]
[exclaims]
[breathing heavily]
[whimpering]
[emotional music continues playing]
[playing drums]
Choisseung was going to
bring me something, so--
[Mi-suk] Talk to him later!
People will talk if they see you here.
Mom.
Are you ashamed of me?
That's right.
I don't even want to see your face.
You're sleeping all day
and fooling around.
Didn't it ever occur to you to wonder
how sleep-deprived I must've been?
Or how little fun I must have had
all these years to fool around like that?
Everyone has it hard. You're not special.
Try having kids of your own.
See if you can treat
your sick child that way.
-Are you taking his side again?
-[objects clattering]
Is being sick that big of a deal?
[continues playing drum]
[sobbing]
[playing drums slowly]
[sniffles]
[groans]
[crying] Why my Seok-ryu?
Why did she have to get cancer?
Why did she have to get sick like that?
[sobbing]
If anyone, it should've been me.
All she ever did was work hard.
She did nothing wrong.
That poor child. [sobbing]
My goodness.
My goodness…
No, my poor girl.
Seok-ryu.
[continues sobbing]
What am I going to do? My poor girl.
[emotional music continues playing]
[knock on door]
[door opens]
[Hye-suk] Seung-hyo.
What's that?
[Hye-suk] Porridge.
You didn't seem well,
so I asked Mi-suk to make it.
I just can't believe what's happened.
Did you come into my room before?
Yeah.
Just leave it here. I'll eat this later.
I heated it. Before it cools, you…
[sighs]
[Hye-suk] Okay.
Rest up.
But did you really not know?
You went to the US
on a business trip three years ago.
You didn't see her then?
-I'm almost there.
-[phone vibrating]
What's this?
MO-EUM
-Hey.
-Hey, Seung-hyo.
-I heard you're in the US.
-How did you know that?
[Mo-eum] Aunt Mi-suk told me.
This is great.
Can you go and see
Seok-ryu while you're there?
She's been so busy I can't reach her.
Hey, do you think I have time to waste?
Don't be like that. Go and see her.
You two are in the same world now.
It's a six-hour plane ride
from New York to California.
I see.
Well, that's practically another country.
I guess they're different worlds.
Got it? Good. Bye.
[line disconnects]
[footsteps approaching]
[inhales]
[slow music playing]
Back then,
I should've run to Seok-ryu.
I should've told her she looked thin
and that she looked tired.
I should've asked her if she was okay.
Could you display the screen in the back?
Please take a look at the documents.
Create new floor plans
to prevent construction errors.
-[man] Okay.
-[phone vibrating]
BAE SEOK-RYU
[lady] Has CAD work
for landscaping started?
[man] Yes.
HEY, YOU'RE IN THE US?
WHY DIDN'T YOU CALL?
Share the bill of quantities
once the working design is complete.
-Any issues with the schedule, right?
-[man] No.
Choi Seung-hyo is a true captain.
You understand? In the sea of life,
we won't get lost with him!
He navigates the way for us.
This is all thanks to him.
Do you all know that?
-You're drunk.
-Hey.
What's that? Who's calling this late?
SEOK-RYU
HOW ARE YOU? YOU MUST BE BUSY
It's nothing.
Hey, you like dried pollock.
[pop song playing]
[mouse clicking]
[phone vibrating]
HAPPY BIRTHDAY, CHOISSEUNG
THANKS
[exhales]
[sighs softly]
[Seung-hyo] But I was a coward,
and while I'd been out of reach,
she was sick.
Without anyone knowing
and alone for a long time.
When I was hurt,
Seok-ryu was the only person
who dragged me out of my cave.
But…
she sent all those signals in the dark,
and I missed them all.
BEAR IN THE CAVE
[birds chirping]
[door opens]
[Mi-suk] What are you doing?
Hey.
Are you making porridge?
[Geun-sik] Yeah.
Take these.
[exclaims softly]
How did you think of freezing these?
It'll upset her
if she sees that our eyes are swollen.
Right.
[Seok-ryu] What are you two doing?
Honey, the porridge.
It's boiling over.
[Geun-sik] Goodness.
I almost wasted all this great porridge.
I'm making abalone porridge.
Because of me?
I don't need to eat porridge.
You should eat food that's easy to digest.
You almost choked on abalone rice before.
[exclaims]
I just had something in my throat then.
I even ate the tteokbokki
you made me last time.
You're right.
Why would you eat that?
You should've said no.
It's good. Why wouldn't I eat it?
Dad, I'm fine. Don't worry.
Still, be careful.
Take me with you
when you visit the doctor next time.
What for? You don't have to come.
Okay, you can come.
Dad, the porridge.
Jeez! I turned down the heat,
but it's still boiling over.
Gosh, I burnt the bottom. [chuckles]
It'll still taste good.
[Jae-suk] Hey.
What do you mean?
Seok-ryu has cancer?
I heard it myself,
but I still don't believe it.
I don't know how this happened.
Hang up. I'm going to call Mi-suk.
Hey, don't.
Just leave her be
until she tells us herself.
Don't act like you know.
How can I do that?
Hey, you might be able to do that,
but I can't!
-I'd rather go and comfort her.
-[door closes]
[voice shaking] Imagine the hard time
she's going through!
Her daughter has cancer.
Mom, what did you just say?
Seok-ryu, you crazy…
[breath trembling]
-How could you hide that?
-Yeah, I hid it.
I didn't tell you. I kept it a secret.
What the hell?
You thought I'd go easy on you
if you confessed?
Don't go easy on me.
What are you doing?
Are you turning yourself in?
I know I deserve to get chewed out.
So do as much as you desire.
No.
I don't do anything that's made easy.
You're not qualified to be a hero.
They love getting things handed to them.
You're right.
I'm not qualified.
I couldn't save you.
Why would you suddenly
say something like that?
A tteokbokki fanatic
suddenly can't eat spicy food.
You drank non-alcoholic beer.
When I think about it,
there were so many clues.
I should've figured it out. Damn it.
Maybe I'm good at acting.
Should I pursue acting instead of cooking?
Did your mom cry a lot?
[sighs] My parents had spoons
on their eyes like this in the morning.
They looked like Ultraman.
I won't cry.
I'll never cry.
If you won't cry or cuss me out,
what will you do?
Well…
I will…
do this.
[slow music playing]
You should've hugged me
like this at the airport.
You're right.
You've endured so much, Seok-ryu.
Physically and mentally.
Thanks.
Just so you know,
you're really flat.
[laughing] I don't feel a thing.
What are you talking about?
We're not even touching!
I'm more curvaceous than you think!
I doubt that.
Want me to get undressed?
-Go ahead.
-I'll really do it.
I meant you're too skinny.
Buy me something nice to eat
if you feel sorry for me.
-I'm paid in peanuts.
-I'm unemployed.
-Should we buy lottery tickets?
-How many?
-How about seven?
-No.
Make it an even number.
It's easier to split.
Okay, let's buy ten!
Sounds good. [chuckles]
[Mo-eum] All right, then.
[both laughing]
Professor, we just had people
from a car accident come in.
The car went up onto the sidewalk
and crashed into a building.
How's are the patients?
The scans show
a pelvic bone fracture in one patient.
One has a clavicle fracture,
and another has a hip fracture.
Let me see.
Bae Seok-ryu?
What?
Oh.
This patient was here a few days ago.
She had surgery
for stomach cancer in the US.
I remembered
because of her unique name.
[solemn music playing]
[sighs]
The client requested a new contractor?
[Myeong-u] Oh.
Why?
He wants to let an acquaintance do it.
The brother-in-law
of his father-in-law's
high school classmate
has a construction firm.
Isn't that a stranger?
Yeah.
But during construction,
the client thinks we could mess with
material and labor costs.
They said they couldn't trust our choice.
[Na-yun] Are they crazy?
Why did they trust us
with the design then?
Switch it for them.
-What?
We should carry out our client's request.
Get their number, contact them,
and schedule a meeting.
I'll call Mr. Bang
from Sunjong Construction and apologize.
-Yes, sir.
-[Seung-hyo] All right.
Let's wrap up today's meeting.
Keep up the great work.
Wow.
Normally, he would've never allowed this.
He must be in a really good mood today.
No, it's the opposite.
Something's up with him.
I have to ask you something.
Are you free?
[Gyeong-jong] So you knew.
I was debating whether to call you or not.
You know about her condition, right?
Even if you're my son,
I can't release a patient's information.
Can you just tell me if she's okay?
Seung-hyo.
I've always liked Seok-ryu.
A lot of people are awkward with me,
but she never was.
I adored that about her. I was grateful.
Bring Seok-ryu to the hospital.
I'll make sure she's okay.
I promise you.
Okay, Dad.
[both] Mi-suk!
[Jae-suk] Hey, are you okay?
You look so drawn today.
-You didn't get any sleep, did you?
-Mi-suk.
There's an herbal medicine clinic I know.
I asked them what's good
for the stomach.
Cabbages and broccoli.
-And lotus root. Lotus root is great.
-Did you tell them?
Yeah.
Why did you go
and do something I didn't ask for?
It's not like that.
She told us to pretend
like we didn't know.
We're just worried.
Goodness. You even asked them
to act like they didn't know?
Mi-suk, it's not like that.
We just wanted to comfort you.
Why would you comfort me?
Who said I wanted that?
No one asked you to do this!
Na Mi-suk.
You're in one of the five stages of grief.
You're passing through anger.
But that's expected and natural.
You're really something too.
You want to brag
about how smart you are right now?
Fine, just get angry.
Be as angry as you want!
Just take it out on us!
-What?
-You can do that.
We're your friends.
Friends?
So what?
Are friends allowed
to cross the line like this?
Hey, don't talk to me
if you've never experienced it before.
You're right. We haven't.
But we know. Because we're parents too.
We know how you'd rather suffer
in Seok-ryu's place
and how much you blame yourself.
[In-suk crying] Yeah, Mi-suk.
You act tough on the outside,
but we know how sensitive you are.
We know how delicate you are.
[Mi-suk] Goodness.
What am I going to do with Seok-ryu?
[voice shaking] I didn't
even know she was sick.
I'm no mother.
I'm not qualified to be a mother.
My gosh. [sobbing]
-Hey, Mi-suk.
-Mi-suk! [crying]
[all sobbing]
[Hye-suk] No, don't blame yourself.
Okay?
It's okay.
Just cry, you brat. Cry it all out.
[phone vibrating]
SE-HWAN: WHERE ARE YOU?
[insects trilling]
STOMACH CANCER
SURVIVAL RATE RISES TO 78%
EARLY DETECTION AND PREVENTION ARE KEY
[groans]
Bae Seok-ryu.
She looks strong enough to eat rocks.
How could she get sick?
-Damn it.
-[Na-yun exclaiming]
[Dong-jin] Are you okay?
No, I'm not okay. I almost got hurt.
-You're our gym member.
-[Na-yun] What?
What are you doing here?
-Shouldn't you be at work?
-[Dong-jin] Oh.
I quit.
That place wasn't big enough
for someone like me.
I see. So you were fired.
No, I wasn't!
I left on my own.
You were about to be fired,
so you quit first.
No, I didn't!
Take this advice from someone who's had
more experience in the workplace.
Get on your knees
and beg for your job back.
Why would I?
You don't know anything.
Why are you meddling?
Meddling?
That's not something I ever do.
I'm just giving you advice
after what you did with the treadmill.
[pleasant music playing]
I was running too fast back then.
Hey, your strides are too long!
[Na-yun] I can't hear you.
The optimal cadence
for running is 180 bpm.
So what cadence is…
I think you hear me.
[Na-yun] Jeez.
Ms. Jung.
Ms. Jung?
[exclaims]
[both grunt]
[Mo-eum exclaiming]
[dog barks distantly]
-[Dan-ho exclaiming in pain]
-[Mo-eum sobbing]
-[coughs]
-[Mo-eum continues sobbing]
[weakly] Ms. Jung.
[Mo-eum] Slowly.
[mellow music playing]
-Be careful when you sit.
-Okay.
[Mo-eum grunts softly]
[Dan-ho exhales]
[Mo-eum] Are you okay?
Let's just go to the hospital.
I think you need an X-ray.
It's fine.
Who knew I'd end up
feeling the power of a black belt?
[chuckles softly]
You should've known how to avoid it
if you were a red belt.
[chuckles softly]
Do you have pain relief patches?
[Dan-ho] Um…
-No.
-Wait here. I'll go buy some.
It's fine, so just sit for a second.
[Mo-eum] Maybe I have some at my house.
I'm really okay.
I'm not that weak.
I didn't say anything.
[exhales]
Can I ask why you were crying back there?
Why are you asking to ask
when you've already done so?
-You're right.
-[chuckles softly]
The thing is…
this is actually a very popular place
for listening to people's problems.
I've already had someone here before.
Who? Choi Seung-hyo?
Oh.
How did you know?
Well, the security maintenance here
seemed like a mess.
Oh.
[scoffs] No wonder.
You see,
it's about a friend of mine, not me.
My friend has a really close friend.
They've been best friends
since they were kids.
That friend lived abroad for a long time.
I see.
[Mo-eum] But…
my friend's friend…
Um…
had surgery…
for cancer three years ago.
And my friend
just found out recently.
Your friend must be having
a really hard time.
But…
she keeps acting
like she's not having a hard time.
[slow music playing]
But it's killing me.
[gasps]
I mean, I'm not talking about me.
It's my friend. And my friend's friend.
Why is this so confusing?
It's not about me.
It's my friend's friend.
Don't worry.
I'll make sure
security is tighter this time.
[groans softly]
Well…
I can't believe Seok-ryu's sick.
Due to the nature of my job,
I see a lot of sick people.
And people on the verge of death.
But…
[voice shaking] …I never imagined that
Seok-ryu could be one of those people.
[sniffles]
I said I wouldn't cry, but I can't stop.
You can cry here.
What?
Cry a little bit here in secret.
Then, smile even more after that.
Share a drink with her.
Chat, have fun, and just be with her.
[sniffles]
Being with someone
who miraculously returned
is a miracle in itself.
[slow music continues playing]
It's just like what Yeon-du means to me.
-Yeon-du?
-[Dan-ho] Yes.
It was two years ago.
I looked at my phone
after finishing an interview.
I'd several missed calls
from the same number.
I called back and they said
it was the hospital.
[panting]
[man] Is this her?
[inhales, breath trembling]
[breathing heavily]
[breath trembling]
My child.
[voice shaking] I have a child.
Where is she?
KANG YEON-DU
DO HYEON-WOO
IN SURGERY
[slow music continues playing]
[sniffles]
Yeon-du…
miraculously survived the accident
and came back to me.
[Mo-eum] Dan-ho…
So I know how precious
each ordinary morning is.
Waking her up every morning,
feeding her breakfast,
running to daycare together
so she's not late,
and seeing her wave goodbye to me
as she walks inside.
Ordinary days like that.
So you should also…
You said it was okay to cry.
Why are you holding it in?
[mellow music playing]
I'll keep it secret too.
[Dan-ho grunting]
[quirky music playing]
[mutters]
[panting]
[breathing heavily]
What's the point of running away?
I live next door.
[door closes]
[music ends]
[jazz music playing in the background]
[Hye-suk] Sorry.
I forgot we were supposed to
have lunch together.
That's okay.
We can just have dinner together.
I must be getting old.
I've never made such mistakes before.
What? It's cute.
[Hye-suk] Thank you.
Seo Hye-suk's doing things
unlike her usual self.
My gosh. What's this?
Chablis wine. Nice, right?
It's so nice.
As for me,
I'm used to hearing adjectives
like "beautiful" and "cool."
But "cute"? That's not bad either.
[both chuckle]
Cheers.
Mmm.
This really is nice.
What did you need to discuss with me?
Well…
Have you thought about my offer?
I see.
That?
[Hye-suk] What's this?
Why did you come here?
Well…
I had something to tell you.
What do you mean? Take time off?
It's how it sounds.
You've been overdoing things.
[scoffs]
I didn't overdo things. I just worked.
Right.
"The Woman of the Wind
who crossed the Sahara Desert."
"The Foreign Ministry's African Tongue."
Jeez. Go get everyone
who gave me those names.
-I'll teach them.
-[chuckles]
You've lived up to your names
by being in the field
for over 20 years now.
Let's take a break.
Let's eat and have tea at our leisure.
I know that you're worried.
But I want to stay on active duty.
I'm years away from retirement too.
I'll speak to the minister myself
and ask him where I should go.
You…
can't go anywhere.
What?
Because…
you won't be reassigned.
Oh. [chuckles]
I bet there aren't
any suitable positions right now.
I'll wait then.
It doesn't matter which country it is.
-When a spot opens, anywhere is--
-There's no point in waiting.
You understand what I mean, right?
You're telling me to just collect my pay
while on standby with no job?
-Don't tell me…
-You'll hear soon.
You'll be asked to voluntarily resign.
[scoffs]
Did you agree with it too?
It was an organizational decision.
Sure.
Then, I'll have to accept it.
[sighs softly]
You're mad at me, right?
No.
Then, why didn't you call me?
I was busy.
Liar. You were avoiding me.
I know. It's because of my cancer.
It bothers you to look at me.
You don't know if you need to
comfort me or encourage me.
You probably don't know what to say.
Hey, it's like that at my house too.
My mom's crying.
My dad's having a hard time.
Even Dong-jin's become pale with fear.
They walk on eggshells around me.
It's so uncomfortable.
I knew this would happen.
That's why I kept it a secret.
But no one understands
how thoughtful I was being.
Yeah, right.
Seok-ryu, you're saying
you kept this a secret for our sake?
No, you only thought about yourself.
You're a coward, and you're pathetic.
What?
You're weak and hypocritical.
Hey.
You…
hurt the people who love you.
You did the unthinkable.
[slow music playing]
To your mom, your dad, me.
And to yourself.
You…
in your loneliest
and most difficult moment,
left yourself alone.
Seok-ryu.
When things are really tough,
you lean on the people closest to you.
What if I did lean on them?
Would that have changed anything?
If I'm hurting,
you'd all be hurting with me.
If I fall, you'd fall with me
like dominoes.
Who cares if we fall?
Who cares if things crumble?
We can hit rock bottom together.
Then, we can get back up again.
I don't know how to do that.
This is who I am,
so what can I do?
You did it for me!
When my mom left for Africa
and when I had to quit swimming
because I hurt my leg,
you reached out to me.
You stayed with me.
Hey.
That's…
That's different.
But why won't you give me
the chance to do the same?
You did all those things for me.
Why won't you let me do the same for you?
That's enough.
Let's stop.
Seok-ryu. Are you running away again?
Stop!
I said stop!
[sighs]
I should've done the same back then.
Just like you,
I should've shouted and gotten angry.
I should've been more honest.
Back then,
was Seok-ryu…
in a lot of pain?
She endured it courageously.
[sighs]
[exclaims]
[groans]
[Geun-sik exclaims]
[sighs]
I thought the alcohol
would be sweet, but it's bitter.
[liquid pouring]
[exhales]
That's good.
We can split this bottle
and go to bed.
[both sigh]
Honey.
[exhales]
I keep thinking about all the wrong things
I've done to Seok-ryu.
When Seok-ryu was three,
Dong-jin was crying at night.
She woke up and started to cry too.
So I scolded her.
I said, "You're a big kid.
Why are you crying?"
"Why are you giving me a hard time too?"
You were young.
You didn't know.
Still…
I shouldn't have done that.
I think I made this happen to her.
My excuse was I had to
give Dong-jin extra care,
and I pushed her too much to the side.
But…
she grew up so well on her own.
Yeah, she did.
Our daughter…
never caused us any trouble. [inhales]
[voice shaking] That poor girl
must've tried so hard to do that.
She must've been so stressed.
[both whimpering]
But all I did
was boast about it to others.
I never gave her
the support she needed. [sniffles]
She was so worried
that she endured such an awful thing…
[sniffles] …all on her own. [sobbing]
[voice shaking] It's mostly my fault.
[breath trembling]
Gosh, that restaurant was doomed anyway.
Why did I try so hard?
[slow music playing]
I wasn't able to focus
on my family. [sniffles]
I passed it off onto you.
[sobbing, sniffles]
I feel terrible for what I did to her.
What am I going to do? [sobbing]
I'm so sorry.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry to you. [sniffles]
And I'm sorry to Seok-ryu.
Honey, what do we do? [sobbing]
[Geun-sik whimpering]
[both whimpering]
[Mi-suk sobbing] I'm so sorry.
[Geun-sik] I'm sorry. [sobbing]
I'm so…
[voice shaking] I'm sorry.
[Mi-suk sobbing] Honey,
what are we going to do?
[music ends]
[birds chirping]
[exhales]
[door closes]
[amusing music playing]
I can't even greet Yeon-du
because of my careless lips.
All of this happened
because I had a lot on my mind.
As a result, it short-circuited a little.
Let's put out the fire.
I have to extinguish it.
[breathes deeply]
Why did she hide?
Is she playing hide-and-seek?
-What are you talking about?
-Mo-eum just hid after she saw us.
I saw her.
We're late. Yeon-du, should we run?
-Yeah.
-[Dan-ho] Ready, set, go!
[Yeon-du] I'm going to beat you!
[Yeon-du talking indistinctly]
Hey, Seok-ryu.
Seok-ryu?
She left her phone. Where did she go?
[phone vibrating]
JEONGHEON UNIVERSITY HOSPITAL
BAE SEOK-RYU, YOUR BIOPSY RESULTS ARE OUT
[exhales]
[slow music playing]
[indistinct conversation]
[Seung-hyo] Back then,
was Seok-ryu…
in a lot of pain?
She endured it courageously.
[sighs]
At least,
that's what I thought.
[slow music continues playing]
After her surgery,
about a year passed…
and she developed depression.
Depression?
I didn't know.
She was falling apart alone.
[metal bangs]
[supervisor] Be careful!
[employee] Yes, sir!
Please be careful.
Mr. Choi, could you come here?
Can you explain this?
[Seung-hyo] Sure.
[Myeong-u] Here.
So this isn't your average structure.
I thought it'd be hard to implement.
I'll send you a detailed floor plan
and additional materials to explain.
We'd be grateful for that.
As for that area, if you look here…
[phone vibrating]
Just a moment. Sorry.
Hi, Aunt Mi-suk.
What? Seok-ryu?
[mellow music playing]
[indistinct chatter]
[sighs softly]
[doorbell chiming]
[exhales]
[panting]
HYEREUNG COOKING SCHOOL
[exhales]
[mellow music continues playing]
[tires screech]
Seriously?
[music ends]
Hey, Seok-ryu!
Choisseung?
What are you doing?
How did you know I was here?
If you're going to go somewhere,
you should let people know!
How could you disappear
without your phone?
Well, that…
interferes with my deep meditation
and self-reflection--
[Seung-hyo] Are you joking?
Do you know how much
I've been looking for you?
Do you know how worried everyone is?
I came here
because I was frustrated, okay?
I need to breathe too.
Hey.
Because of you,
I'm the one who's suffocating here.
How long were you
going to keep it a secret?
going to hide it for?
You want to talk about this again?
Aren't you sick of it already?
Your emotional pain,
not your physical pain.
You…
had depression.
Why didn't you tell me?
Where did you hear that?
Did you see Hyeon-jun?
Seriously, what's wrong with you?
Are you a fool?
Why are you so stupid?
How much have you bottled up
in that tiny body of yours?
Stop it. I'm leaving.
[sighs]
[Seok-ryu exclaims] Hey!
What are you doing?
What on earth are you doing?
Hey!
Wait! What are you doing?
[waves splashing]
[Seok-ryu screams]
Hey, what are you doing?
Are you insane?
[screaming]
[mellow music playing]
What are you doing, you lunatic?
You said you were frustrated.
Isn't it refreshing now?
Hey!
[Seung-hyo] Yeah.
You should shout like that.
[pop song playing]
You have everything pent up inside.
Let it all out.
What's inside you is bitterness.
So…
don't try to foolishly
carry that burden alone!
Let it all out here.
Why are you yelling at me?
Why do you keep getting angry at me?
I'm the one who was sick.
I'm the one who's having the hardest time.
[voice shaking] Why do you
keep scolding me?
I wasn't being angry at you.
I'm mad at myself.
After I heard you were sick,
I thought back.
I didn't hear you…
knocking on my door.
You sent me signs
that you were struggling.
But I had my eyes and ears closed.
Even though I knew that…
I said those harsh things to you.
I felt so pathetic and frustrated.
I felt like garbage.
Why didn't you text me back?
I'm sorry.
Why did you ignore my calls?
[crying]
I wasn't able to tell anyone!
Do you know how scared I was on my own?
Why did you do that?
I was so worried my parents
would collapse from shock if I told them!
I had all sorts of thoughts
in my head when I made this decision.
I debated if I should tell you or not
over a hundred times. [sobbing]
You don't know anything!
You don't know how I feel!
[continues crying]
[waves splashing]
Here.
Nothing beats banana milk
after going for a swim.
[chuckles softly]
It's nice. It's like when we'd visit
the bathhouse as kids.
[Seung-hyo exhales]
[Seok-ryu] Mmm.
Hey, you haven't answered me yet.
How did you know I was here?
This is where you ran away to before.
It was short-lived though.
You didn't have to say that part.
It's true that I ran away.
It was justified too.
Mom.
How come only he gets a new phone?
How come only Dong-jin
gets a new phone?
Gosh, I had no choice. His was broken.
Mine's broken too. It broke twice.
But I had it fixed!
I said I'd buy you one
if you got the highest mock exam score.
-But you didn't.
-[coughing]
He's the dumbest kid in school,
but you bought him one!
This takes great pictures.
-They're killer!
-Delete them or I'll kill you.
-[Mi-suk] Seung-hyo, are you okay?
-Yeah.
[Mi-suk] Look, you think I wanted
to buy him one?
I can't reach this brat without a phone!
Also, all gadgets are the same.
Try to be more like Seung-hyo.
He's been using the same phone for years.
But he's never complained once.
-What a sweet boy.
-[Seok-ryu] Mom, listen.
Only his phone is old.
Everything else he owns is expensive.
-[groans]
-Look at this. This shirt?
-Let go. Get your hands off me.
-It's over 100,000 won!
And he only wears
foreign-brand underwear. Look!
What are you doing?
-[Mi-suk] Stop!
-Are you crazy?
This is so unfair, Mom.
How come only he gets
a swivel phone and not me?
[voice shaking] You always let
stuff like this happen!
It's not fair!
[pleasant music playing]
[waves splashing]
Jeez, what is wrong with her?
I want to go back!
You wore your uniform to school,
went to all your classes,
and then ran away.
Does that even count?
Absences would lower your grades.
Fine, forget it.
I didn't have much guts.
It's because you're too nice.
[pleasant music continues playing]
What?
You were mad
and felt things were unfair,
but you didn't want to worry your parents.
So that was your compromise.
My brother was always causing problems.
But I was the one
who caused the biggest mess.
[slurping]
I'm done.
[sighs audibly]
I'd wish for nothing more
than a cold beer to chug right now.
But I can't do that anymore.
That makes me sad.
Make the call.
To who?
My dad.
They said you got a text
from the hospital.
Your biopsy results are out.
That? Later. I can do that later.
Not later. Do it now while I'm here.
Do you remember when they put
seven metal pins in my leg?
Yeah. Why?
Did something happen when you stubbed
your foot into the bed that time?
What? No.
But once you injure a knee,
it can get hurt again.
If that happens, I'm going to
take you with me to the hospital.
Don't I get any say in it?
I'm going to make you buy me juice.
And what else? I'll make you
get comic books for me.
-And I'll ask you to wash my greasy hair.
-[scoffs]
That's ridiculous.
Who says I'll do it?
I'd do it for you.
That's what I'm going to do
no matter what you say.
So…
don't worry that something might happen.
Call them,
and I'll stay by your side.
[slow music playing]
[Seok-ryu sighs]
FATHER
[line ringing]
Hello, sir. It's Seok-ryu.
Yes.
I'm sorry I hid it from you.
So…
I heard the biopsy results are out.
Right.
Okay.
Oh.
Okay, I understand.
Okay, bye.
What did he say?
He said it was nothing.
It was just an infection. I'm clean.
[sighs deeply]
[pleasant music playing]
[exhales]
-Hey, why the hell are you hugging me?
-Just…
Let me give you a damn hug.
[sighs deeply]
Goodness.
Gosh.
[sighs wearily]
[pleasant music continues playing]
-[clears throat]
-[line ringing]
Where are you right now?
Professor, are you going to eat?
Yeah.
The cafeteria's serving bibimbap today.
I'm going to have steak.
What? They're serving steak?
Professor, where…
The cafeteria's this way.
Professor?
[music ends]
[dramatic music playing]
[female 1] It's the vice minister
and ambassador.
-[female 1] Didn't they graduate together?
-[female 2] Yeah, they're really close.
They went to Africa together
in the past too.
What's with the flowers?
[female 3] Who knows?
There are tons of rumors about them.
It's well-known. They say
the vice minister isn't married yet
because the ambassador still is.
[female 1 gasps] That's insane.
[music ends]
Hey, Mo-eum did the same thing too.
Why are you expressing
your friendship with hugs now?
Not me.
I told you we're not friends anymore.
We're here.
It's so quick without the traffic.
Where are we going? That was my house.
Wait, where are we going?
Hello? Where are we going?
My legs are falling asleep.
-Mom.
-Yeah?
Do we have to do all this?
I know from experience,
but a surprise party requires patience.
-Hang in there.
-When is Seok-ryu coming?
The food's getting cold.
-Aunt Mi-suk.
-Yeah?
-This cake didn't come with any matches.
-[Geun-sik] Huh?
That can't be.
Does anyone have a lighter?
I may drink, but I don't smoke.
Should I start smoking again then?
How can you not have
lighters in a kitchen?
Well, yeah. It's a kitchen.
I have a torch. Hold on.
-I'll shine a light.
-Where was it?
-Help him find it.
-It's so dark. I can't see.
My legs.
[Seung-hyo] Hey, wait. Slow down.
-[Seok-ryu] For what?
-[Seung-hyo] Okay?
[Seung-hyo] Hey.
[Mi-suk] It works.
-The door's unlocked.
-Slow down.
[amusing music playing]
CONGRATULATIONS
SEOK-RYU'S WELCOME HOME PARTY
[Seok-ryu] My gosh!
-Surprise!
[all cheering]
Mom, Dad? What's going on?
Well, so…
We wanted to throw a party
to welcome you back home.
[laughs] But I've been home
for some time now.
This is so cheesy. Whose idea was this?
It was him.
Him.
[Seok-ryu] This is ridiculous.
[Geun-sik] What will you do?
[line ringing]
Aunt Mi-suk, I found Seok-ryu.
Yeah. But I was thinking.
How about we give her
a welcome home party tonight?
I know it's a little late,
but we didn't do anything for her
when she came home.
What are you doing?
I mean, I just… [clears throat]
I just wanted to
have a meal with everyone.
You prepared a lot, Uncle Geun-sik.
-Because you told me to.
-Okay, then!
-Come in.
-Let's sit, everyone.
-Sit down.
-Yeah, let's sit.
Goodness!
Chef, please introduce tonight's dishes.
[all cheering]
-What's with you all? [laughs]
-[all laughing]
It's been a while for me.
I'm a little nervous. [laughs]
Wait a second. All right.
Tonight's main dish is
gungjung tteokbokki, which was served
originally during the Joseon Dynasty.
It has rice cakes made with
organic brown rice fresh from the mill.
They've been cooked and reduced
in the chef's special sauce
for the person I love the most
in the whole world…
[sniffles]
For my daughter,
I present this special dish. [chuckles]
-[Dong-jin] A round of applause!
-[all clapping]
Thanks, Dad.
This is the only type of tteokbokki
you can eat now. Got it?
Okay.
Weren't you worried the food
would get cold? What a long speech.
-Let's eat.
-Goodness!
You should say a few words too.
-[Dong-jin] Yeah.
-Hey! No.
-A speech to welcome her home.
-Hurry up.
-I'll do it sitting down.
-[laughs]
We're a family.
[pleasant music playing]
A family doesn't just share
the good times.
A family shares the difficult, sad,
and painful times together too.
So…
from now on,
no more keeping things to yourself.
[Dong-jin] No more.
That's our family motto now.
-Our motto!
-Sounds good!
Friends are family too!
-Family!
-Just join our family. [laughs]
We have so many kids.
We have four of them.
We've always been family.
That's right.
[Mo-eum] Yeah. Hey.
But what do we do about the cake?
We didn't light it.
It's fine. Our surprise failed.
Don't do it.
No, we can have it for dessert later.
-[Mo-eum] Yeah, okay.
-[Geun-sik] Okay.
This is fried yam.
Yams are good for the stomach.
I'm going to grate and fry them
for your breakfast and dinner.
-You better eat them all.
-[Dong-jin] Hey.
Eat up.
How dare you talk that way
your older sister?
You brat!
-Her name's not "Hey."
-Be respectful.
[Mi-suk] Do it now.
Seok-ryu, eat up.
-[Mo-eum exclaims]
-[Geun-sik chuckles]
-[Seok-ryu] Let's eat!
-Thanks for the food!
Thank you for the meal.
[indistinct chatter, laughter]
[music ends]
[Mo-eum grunts]
-I'm so full.
-[laughs]
My stomach might explode.
[dog barks distantly]
-What?
-[Geun-sik] What?
No, it's not what I meant.
That's how good the food was.
I ate a lot.
That's what I meant.
Seriously, I'm okay. Don't worry.
-You scared us.
-[Dong-jin sighs]
-[Mo-eum] She says she's fine.
-All right.
Come up to the rooftop tomorrow.
I'll be your personal trainer.
Are you insane?
Why would I entrust my body to you?
I'll help you too.
-Honorary paramedic, Bae Seok-ryu.
-So cheesy!
-Gross.
-[Mo-eum] Hey, call 119.
I'll come faster than anyone
from the dispatch center.
[chuckles softly] I love
getting this type of treatment.
My dad's going to
make me gungjung tteokbokki.
That's not all.
I'll make you whatever you want,
three square meals a day.
-Of course.
-Then, what about you?
Will you build me a house?
[scoffs] Don't get your hopes up.
-That sounds good.
-Seung-hyo.
It was worth a try.
-Aunt Mi-suk!
-What about you, Mom?
I'll scrub your back.
Let's go to the bathhouse tomorrow.
Okay, let's go.
[Geun-sik chuckles]
Want to come too? Just like old times?
Why would I go with you?
You lunatic. Don't be ridiculous.
I mean, we can just go
to the bathhouse together.
Then, we'll part ways
in front of the lockers.
-What were you thinking?
-[Mi-suk] Yeah.
[Seung-hyo] I wasn't thinking
about anything. Jeez.
[Mo-eum] He's stuttering.
He was thinking.
-[Seok-ryu] He's flustered.
-[Mo-eum] He did!
[Mi-suk] Hey, stop ganging up
on Seung-hyo!
-You did? Why you…
-I didn't!
-[Geun-sik] Come here!
-[Seung-hyo] I'm innocent!
Why is he going in?
[Geun-sik] You better have
that house built!
[indistinct chatter, laughter]
[slow music playing]
[music ends]
[door opens]
[door closes]
[Hye-suk] You're home late.
I'm sorry. I couldn't make it to lunch.
No, it's fine.
Things were hectic for me too,
so I forgot.
Honey.
I have something to tell you.
[sighs]
So do I.
Go ahead. Mine might take a while.
Let's get a divorce.
What?
I want a divorce.
[phone vibrating]
HYEON-JUN
[exhales]
Hello?
[Hyeon-jun] You picked up.
I'm glad.
I have no reason not to.
Where are you?
Where else? I'm at my hotel.
[Seok-ryu] Did you have something to say?
Yeah.
I'm going back to the US.
I think…
this call might be
the last one I give you.
[slow music playing]
Seok-ryu.
I…
loved you so much.
But…
[sighs]
…I think the way I loved you was wrong.
I only focused on
getting you back on your feet.
I never thought to fall down with you.
It was only after I came to Korea…
that I realized who the people
you truly needed were…
and where you needed to be.
I'm sorry.
Back then,
I couldn't relate to your pain.
I couldn't accept you…
for who you were.
No, it was my fault.
I used being sick as an excuse
and exploited you.
I was so consumed with my own emotions
that I didn't recognize…
how lonely you were.
Seok-ryu,
let's not regret the time we shared.
Let's remember
how I was everything to you
and how you meant
everything to me back then.
That should be enough then.
Okay.
All right.
Take care.
You too.
[line disconnects]
[sighs]
[slow music continues playing]
[sighs deeply]
[music ends]
[birds chirping]
[door opens]
Hi.
Are you going to work?
Are you going to class?
I asked you first.
What, you think
I'd be getting off work at this hour?
True. Hey, don't work too late.
It's pointless to devote yourself to work.
It's my company. I'll take care of it.
That's true too.
All right, you take care of it,
and have a great day.
[amusing music playing]
You too.
Hey, why are you following me?
[Seung-hyo] I'm not.
I said I'm going to work.
Yeah, I know that. But go a different way.
Before I cook, I need time
to seriously meditate alone.
[dog barking]
Hey, you're following me.
What are you doing?
-Hyeong-chan.
-Yes, sir?
[Seung-hyo] Come here.
Why is the proposal so flat?
Did you finish analyzing
the surrounding area?
-What about the commercial district?
-Not yet.
After we prepare
the construction procedures first--
You did things in the wrong order.
If we review regulations and build
according to those sizes, we're done?
[pop song playing]
You need to work
with the brand in mind from the start.
If we only consider the ratios,
why would the clients come to us?
[Hyeong-chan] I'm sorry.
I'll have it redone.
I don't think
Mr. Choi's in a good mood today.
-No…
-[Seung-hyo] Na-yun.
Yes?
Did you review Misom's flagship store
and its environmental sustainability?
No, not yet.
I asked you to do that a while ago.
You still haven't finished?
I'm sorry.
-Speed it up.
-[Na-yun] Yes, sir.
He's in a great mood today.
[door closes]
He's super happy.
[Seung-hyo] It can bear fruit?
Can it bloom flowers too?
Of course.
Our friend has a lot to do this year.
Then…
What should I do to listen to my tree?
[shop owner] First off,
it needs a lot of sunshine
for around six to ten hours a day.
Also, it likes warm temperatures.
Putting it in a place with a good breeze
will make it feel less humid.
Don't be withering alone again.
Tell me if you have something to say.
I promise…
I'll listen carefully.
POMEGRANATE TREE
[song ends]
[phone vibrating]
[inhales]
[chuckles softly]
Get up now.
[Seok-ryu] What? What is it?
-[Seung-hyo] We have to go somewhere.
-Where?
-[Seung-hyo] There's no time. Get up.
-I can't go like this!
-It's fine.
-You're in a suit.
-What?
-I didn't wash my hair!
You don't have to.
-You lunatic, where are we going?
-[Seung-hyo] There's no time.
Hey.
-Come on.
-Why are we here?
[indistinct announcement]
Why are we here?
Song Hyeon-jun.
Choisseung.
[mellow music playing]
Wait here. I'm first.
Don't tell me you're here to see me off.
With Seok-ryu?
Isn't this why you messaged me?
This is Song Hyeon-jun.
My flight leaves at 10:00 p.m. tonight.
Take care of Seok-ryu.
I did hope it might happen.
But who knew?
How did you get my number?
I asked Mr. Yoon and he gave it to me.
[sighs] Myeong-u, seriously?
I'll bring Seok-ryu over.
You can say goodbye.
I can't give you a lot of time though.
Keep it short and simple.
Keep your distance too.
I'll keep that in mind.
Also, thank you.
For staying…
by her side back then.
[mellow music continues playing]
Go ahead.
Hey, Choisseung.
I'm more petty, immature,
and impatient than you think.
But I think this is right.
Go ahead.
[chuckles softly]
We've already said our goodbyes.
He went overboard, don't you think?
I'm grateful he did it though.
I mean, I would've dressed up
if I knew I was coming here.
It's the last time you'll see me,
and I look terrible.
You're beautiful.
I've never seen you shine so bright.
Thanks.
Also, thank you for everything.
I'm more thankful.
Should we shake hands for one last time?
I know someone's watching,
but I think it'll be okay.
Jeez.
[Hyeon-jun] Be happy.
[sighs]
Don't get sick again.
Yeah, you too.
I hope you meet someone nice.
It seems like you already have.
I really don't like him.
But he's all right.
I'm off.
[pop song playing]
[Seok-ryu sniffles]
[sniffles]
[exhales]
What are you doing?
It's hot in here.
Can you hold it for me?
[Seok-ryu] What am I, a coat rack?
Just do it, will you?
Just stay like that for a second.
BOARDING
LOS ANGELES
[airplane whooshes]
[Seok-ryu] With Seung-hyo's
thoughtfulness,
I cried for a long time that day.
After a while,
I emerged with swollen eyes
and walked out that door with him.
BEAR IN THE CAVE
MOUTH OF THE CAVE
[pop song continues playing]
Subtitle translation by: Sue Mounce